# Sarafina sintioyia sironka

# Wildlife professions

💌 sironkasarafina@gmail.com 📞 Tell .254701523049 👂 Narok 🏴 kenyan

#### **Profile**

Focused on wildlife management professionals with field experience in various locations. Committed to implementing conservation practices and adhering to regulations to protect endangered areas. Skilled in research and reporting and considered a valuable team asset. Hardworking researcher with experience in fully enforcing state hunting and fishing laws. Trained to survey space by ground, air, and water to monitor activities and detect violations. fair and equitable in enforcing legal requirements. To seek and maintain fulltime positions that offer professional challenges utilizing interpersonal, excellent time management, and problem-solving skills.

# **Education**

Diploma in widlife managament, Wildlife research and Training institute	04/2018 – 11/2020 Nakuru county, Kenya
Cerficate in community wildlife management, Wildlife research and Training institute	09/2016 – 05/2018 Nakuru county, Kenya
Kenya Secondary cerficate, Sosit Girls highschool	01/2012 – 11/2015 Kericho , county, Kenya

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Assistant researcher,** Mara elephant project

03/2021 - present

• Monitoring and identification of elephants in the Maasai Mara ecosystem

Narok county, Kenya

- Collecting elephant data through the use of Earth Ranger and GPS
- Reporting sick wildlife and treating them with the KWS vet unit.
- Collaring elephants and monitoring them with the use of an earth ranger
- · Controlling human-wildlife conflict through the use of drones
- Participating in distance survey research through the use of distance ranger surveys
- Creating awareness in the community about the importance of wildlife in the Mara
- I participated in the 2021 wildlife census with the Kenya Wildlife Service at Maasai Mara as part of the data entry team.

# **Intern,** Colobus conservaton center

11/2020 - 02/2021

- Responded to animal welfare calls from primates who had been in accidents, were sick, or were injured.
- planted trees in schools and hotels around the Dian region of Kenya.
- Responsible for tree nursery duties like watering trees and planting others.
- Made organic compost manure.
- conducted a primate census of baboon Sykes and velvet monkeys around the Diani area.
- Did animal care by feeding orphanage primates and washing their cages.
- Assisted in data entry and data management.

Kwale county, Kenya

# **Assistant researcher,** Nairobi National park

11/2019 - 02/2020

• Assisted in research and monitoring of animals in block counts and plant species in the park.

Nairobi county, Kenya

- Created a library of all research on plants and animal species found in the park.
- Assisted in park management and park administration.
- Assisted in human-wildlife conflict and control.
- Participated in Problem animal control.
- Received radio calls from different ranger stations.
- Any other duties assigned by my supervisor

# **Attachment at olera motorogi conservancy,** Olera motorogi conservancy

07/2017 - 08/2017 Narok county, Kenya

- Participated in patrols with a ranger for daily monitoring of wildlife.
- Assisted in office work, filling records, receiving calls, and attending radio calls from different ranger outposts.
- participated in a human-wildlife conflict meeting.
- maintained the availability of sources of water in the conservancy and its impact on the distribution of wildlife and animal movements.

### **Skills**

Research analyze	Research design	
Wildlife monitoring	Wildlife research	
Project monitoring	Techinical writting	
Capture widlife and specimen collections	Good communications skill	
Driving skill	Microsoft office applications, (word, excel, acess, power point)	
Project managament		
GIS Skill	Studying animals behaviors	
Teamworker and callobarations	Planning and conducting	
Flying of Drones	Data entry	

#### Languages

• Kiswahili · English

#### Courses

<b>Drones Training,</b> Mara Elephant project, under Drone space for kenya	present Nairobi, Kenya
Waterborn conservation training, Focus conservations	03/2023 - 03/2023
Animal welfare, San Diego wilflife Alliance	02/2023 - 02/2023
<b>Driving clases,</b> <i>AA Driving schools</i> I also did a defensive drive with AA	12/2022 – 01/2023 Narok county, Kenya

#### References

**Dr jake wall**, *Director of research*, Mara elephant project jake@maraelephantproject.org, Tell no 2547922478256

**Dr stephen Ndambuki**, *senior scientist*, Wildlife research and Training insititute stevemwiu@gmail.com, Tell no 254727998359

**Madam Nancy**, *General manager colobus conservation*, Colobus conservation center Admin@colobusconservations, Tell no 254710389510